// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which one of the following is not a linear data structure?",
    answer: "Binary tree",
    options: [
      "Queue",
      "Stack",
      "Arrays",
      "Binary tree"
    ]
  },

    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which of the following structure allows elements to be inserted or deleted only from one end?",
    answer: "Stack",
    options: [
      "Stack",
      "Queue",
      "List",
      "Linked list"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which sorting algorithm is based on partitioning of array of data into smaller arrays?",
    answer: "Quick sort",
    options: [
      "Merge sort",
      "Heap sort",
      "Bubble sort",
      "Quick sort"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following is a directed tree in which outdegree of each node is less than or equal to two?",
    answer: "Binary tree",
    options: [
      "Unary tree",
      "Ternary tree",
      "Binary tree",
      "Both B and C"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What do we call the memory address of the first element of an array?",
    answer: "Base address",
    options: [
      "Base address",
      "Null address",
      "First address",
      "Floor address"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "In which order does a queue store items?",
    answer: "FIFO (First In First Out) list",
    options: [
      "FIFO (First In First Out) list",
      "Linear tree",
      "Ordered array",
      "LIFO (Last In First Out) list"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 7,
    question: "A vertex of in-degree zero in a directed graph is called a/an",
    answer: "Sink",
    options: [
      "Root vertex",
      "Isolated vertex",
      "Sink",
      "Articulation point"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "A graph is a tree if and only if graph is",
    answer: "Contains no cycles",
    options: [
      "Directed graph",
      "Contains no cycles",
      "Planar",
      "Completely connected"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What is the worst case time for quick sort to sort an array of n elements?",
    answer: "0(log2n)",
    options: [
      "0(n)",
      "0(nlog2n)",
      "0(log2^n)",
      "0(log2n)"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Each attribute of an entity has a defined set of values. This set of values is called a",
    answer: "Domain",
    options: [
      "Mapping",
      "Entity set",
      "Domain",
      "Range"
    ]
  },

    {
    numb: 11,
    question: "An array consists of n elements. We want to create a heap using the elements. The time complexity of building a heap will be in order of",
    answer: "O(n*logn)",
    options: [
      "O(n*n*logn)",
      "O(n*logn)",
      "O(n*n)",
      "O(n *logn *logn)"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Choose the pure virtual function definition from the following",
    answer: "None of the above",
    options: [
      "virtual void f()=0 { }",
      "void virtual f()=0 { }",
      "virtual void f() {} = 0;",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "How do you allocate a matrix using a single pointer in C? (M and N are the number of rows and columns respectively)",
    answer: "int *arr = (int *)malloc(M * N * sizeof(int));",
    options: [
      "int *arr = malloc(M * N * sizeof(int));",
      "int *arr = (int *)malloc(M * N * sizeof(int));",
      "int *arr = (int *)malloc(M + N * sizeof(int))",
      "int *arr = (int *)malloc(M * N * sizeof(arr));"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 14,
    question: "What is the correct way to create an object called myObj of MyClass?",
    answer: "MyClass myObj;",
    options: [
      "class MyClass = new myObj();",
      "class myObj = new MyClass();",
      "new myObj = MyClass();",
      "MyClass myObj;"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 15,
    question: "How do you create a reference variable of an existing variable?",
    answer: "With the & operator",
    options: [
      "With the ref word",
      "With the * operator",
      "With the & operator",
      "With the REF word",
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Can we typecast void * into int *?",
    answer: "Yes",
    options: [
      "Yes",
      "No",
      "Undefined",
      "optDepends on Compiler"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 17,
    question: "The Bellman Ford algorithm returns ____ value.",
    answer: "Boolean",
    options: [
      "Boolean",
      "Integer",
      "String",
      "Double"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What is the pre processing time of Rabin and Karp Algorithm?",
    answer: "θ(m)",
    options: [
      "θ(m^2)",
      "θ(mlogn)",
      "θ(m)",
      "O(n)"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which one of the following given statements possibly contains the error?",
    answer: "select empid where empid = 1009 and Lastname = 'GELLER';",
    options: [
      "select * from emp where empid = 10003;",
      "select empid from emp where empid = 10006;",
      "select empid from emp;",
      "select empid where empid = 1009 and Lastname = 'GELLER';"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "The term \"NTFS\" refers to which on of the following?",
    answer: "New Technology File System",
    options: [
      "New Technology File System",
      "New Tree File System",
      "New Table type File System",
      "Both A and C"
    ]
  },
];







8
